A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H FA317
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Donations
  - Donations - Willard S. Richardson and Robert W. Gumbel Special Fund, 1927-1952 (Box 38, Folder 278)
    List of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions initiated by Willard S. Richardson; Willard S. Richardson's request for small fund for students, bible classes and other special cases, granted by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Creation of emergency relief fund for Arthur W. Packard use under Robert W. Gumbel's custodianship. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson.
    2.1
  - Donations - John D. Rockefeller Pledges, 1937-1938 (Box 38, Folder 279)
    Material on John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s continuing pledges to institutions and individuals, for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s information after John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s death.
    2.2
  - Donations - Corporate Giving, 1947-1960 (Box 38, Folder 280)
    Memos on Socony Vacuum corporate giving, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s policies. Correspondence with Kimball and other businessmen on the subject; legal problems; proposed advisory agency. Printed material. Correspondents include L. F. Kimball, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Dana S. Creel, D. K. Rose.
    2.3
  - Donations - New York Cultural and Educational Fund, 1952 (Box 38, Folder 281)
    Regarding proposed central agency to conduct annual fund raising for public cultural and educational institutions of Greater New York.
    2.4
  - Donations - College Loan Funds, 1954 (Box 38, Folder 0281A)
    Gerard Swopes' ideas and student loan activities; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s reasons for declining to participate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Gerard Swopes.
    2.5
  - Donations - Fund Raising, 1950-1961 (Box 38, Folder 282)
    Memos, printed material on various aspects of fund-raising; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s speech. Soviet view of American philanthropies. Correspondents include Harold J. Seymour, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    2.6
  - Donations - Fund Raising - John Price Jones Company, Incorporated, 1949-1961 (Box 38, Folder 283)
    Printed studies put out by John Price Jones.
- Friends and Relations
  - Friends and Relations - Adams, Miss Antonette, 1907-1939 (Box 39, Folder 284)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. secretary; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. helped with rent; solicitude for her health.
    108Ad
  - Friends and Relations - Adams, Goldie, 1926-1951 (Box 39, Folder 285)
    Crank was John D. Rockefeller, Jr. fellow church member; had crush on John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Sent to rest homes, Gould farm; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid some expenses.
    108Ad1
  - Friends and Relations - Adams, Goldie - Gould Farms, Etc., 1929 (Box 39, Folder 286)
  - Friends and Relations - Albright, Horace M., 1939-1958 (Box 39, Folder 287)
    Family news; comments on National Park projects.
    108Al1
  - Friends and Relations - Albright, Horace M., 1956 (Box 39, Folder 0287A)
  - Friends and Relations - Albright, Horace M. - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1952-1961 (Box 39, Folder 288)
    Friendship; comments on issues of common interest. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Horace Albright.
  - Friends and Relations - Albright, Horace M. - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1956-1960 (Box 39, Folder 288A)
  - Friends and Relations - Albright, Horace M. - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Testimonial Dinner, 1959-1960 (Box 39, Folder 289)
    Rockefeller family contributions to dinner and memorial lectureship.
  - Friends and Relations - Albright, Horace M. - Laurance S. Rockefeller - Testimonial Dinner, 1959-1960 (Box 39, Folder 289A)
  - Friends and Relations - Allen, Dr. Paul, 1899-1915 (Box 39, Folder 290)
    Charges for services; loan to him, gift of automobile.
    108All
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, E. B., 1907-1964 (Box 39, Folder 291)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's brother; disposition of Aldrich effects; friendship with John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Death.
    108Al3
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, E. B. - Regarding Warwick Estate, 1927-1929 (Box 39, Folder 292)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Gifts to Museums, 1951-1955 (Box 39, Folder 293)
    Her dissatisfaction with manner of display in Providence Museum; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid for changes. Abby Aldrich Rockefeller print room; loan and gift of porcelains by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Contributions by David Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller to museum.
    108Al31
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Gifts to Museums, 1951-1955 (Box 39, Folder 293A)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Gifts to Museums, 1948-1950 (Box 39, Folder 294)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - General; Will, 1947-1955 (Box 40, Folder 295)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's sister; arrangements for travel, imports. Gifts to and from her. Personal letters from John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; visits; long newsy John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letters after Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's death. Lucy's death, 1955; will and estate.
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Purchases, 1915-1939 (Box 40, Folder 296)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Importations, 1929-1937 (Box 40, Folder 297)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - General, 1951-1955; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 40, Folder 298)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - General, 1951-1955; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 40, Folder 298A)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - General, 1923-1950; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 40, Folder 299)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - General, 1923-1950; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 40, Folder 299A)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - General, 1922-1925; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 41, Folder 300)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Office Account, 1927-1935 (Box 41, Folder 301)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Regarding 110 Benevolent Street, 1927 (Box 41, Folder 302)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Finances, 1915-1921 (Box 41, Folder 303)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Presents, 1927-1950 (Box 41, Folder 304)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Regarding Death, 1955-1956 (Box 41, Folder 305)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Lucy T. - Regarding Death, 1955-1956 (Box 41, Folder 305A)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, N. W. - General, 1910-1922 (Box 41, Folder 306)
    Boat, death, funeral.
    108Al32
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, N. W. - Program - 1st Annual Republican Dinner, 1887 (Box 41, Folder 307)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, N. W. - The June Munsey, 1896 (Box 41, Folder 308)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, N. W. - Regarding Death, 1915 (Box 41, Folder 309)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, N. W. - Obituary, "Providence Journal", 1915 (Box 41, Folder 310)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, N. W. - Regarding Death of Mrs. Aldrich, 1917 (Box 41, Folder 311)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, William T., 1907-1954 (Box 42, Folder 312)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's brother, was architect, painter; club membership.
    108Al34
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1916-1952; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 42, Folder 313)
    Marriage, military service, law practice; homes; gifts; ambassador to Great Britain. Patrol boat leased to government, 1917.
    108Al35
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1952-1974; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 42, Folder 314)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1953-1966; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 42, Folder 0314A)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Winthrop - Boat for Government Service, 1917-1919 (Box 42, Folder 315)
  - Friends and Relations - Aldrich, Stuart and Richard, 1916-1960 (Box 42, Folder 316)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's brothers; family news; small gifts; deaths. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Stuart Aldrich, Richard Aldrich.
    108Al33
  - Friends and Relations - Allen, Arthur M., 1927-1950 (Box 42, Folder 317)
    Brown classmate of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; comments on Franklin D. Roosevelt's 3rd term, coming of war, John F. Dulles, Martha B. Allen. His widow married John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1951.
    108Al36
  - Friends and Relations - Allen, Arthur M. - Painting by Fred W. Wright, 1951-1952 (Box 42, Folder 318)
  - Friends and Relations - Andrews, E. Benjamin, 1911-1944 (Box 42, Folder 319)
    Gifts to Andrews; his income; last illness.
    108An1
  - Friends and Relations - Andrews, Ryland B., 1912-1926 (Box 43, Folder 320)
    Brown graduate, friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., employed by Prairie Oil Co.
    108An2
  - Friends and Relations - Arnett, Trevor, 1947-1958; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 321)
    Advisor on college matters. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. address on tuition. Personal relations; recollections of busy years; death; tributes to him.
    108Ar
  - Friends and Relations - Arnett, Trevor, 1926-1947; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 322)
  - Friends and Relations - Arnett, Trevor - Salary Arrangement, 1928-1935 (Box 43, Folder 323)
  - Friends and Relations - Astor, Lord and Lady, 1948-1959 (Box 43, Folder 324)
    Friendship; 1953 $6,000 gift.
    108As
  - Friends and Relations - Atterbury, Grosvenor, 1947-1956; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 325)
    Architect, experimented in pre-cast housing; made architectural plans for Seal Harbor and Pocantico Hills. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in him; financial aid during illness. Comments on Henry Stimson. Gifts. Death.
    108At
  - Friends and Relations - Atterbury, Grosvenor, 1932-1947; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 326)
  - Friends and Relations - Atterbury, Grosvenor, 1932; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 0326A)
  - Friends and Relations - Avril de St. Croix, Mme., 1913-1939 (Box 44, Folder 327)
    Frenchwoman interested in White Slavery. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions.
    108Av
  - Friends and Relations - Barlow, Emma Lou, 1939-1962 (Box 44, Folder 328)
    Williamsburg resident; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. financial aid during illness.
    108B1
  - Friends and Relations - Baker, Dwight, 1903-1931 (Box 44, Folder 329)
    Brown graduate worked in office, borrowed money; died in debt.
    108B11
  - Friends and Relations - Baker, Dwight - Financial Assistance, 1919-1931 (Box 44, Folder 330)
  - Friends and Relations - Ballard, Edward L., 1907-1939 (Box 44, Folder 331)
    Friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., associated with Merchants Fire Insurance. Gifts.
    108B12
  - Friends and Relations - Ballard, Mrs. Edward L., 1945-1958 (Box 44, Folder 332)
    Widow of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. friend; her friendship with John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Martha Baird Rockefeller.
  - Friends and Relations - Barbour, C. R., 1923-1930; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 44, Folder 333)
    President of Rochester Theological Institute, then Brown University. Family problems; loans from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. which were repaid; outright gifts.
    108B122
  - Friends and Relations - Barbour, C. R., 1930-1947; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 44, Folder 334)
  - Friends and Relations - Barbour, C. R. - Regarding Gifts, 1924-1925 (Box 45, Folder 335)
  - Friends and Relations - Barbour, C. R. - Regarding Gifts, 1926-1936 (Box 45, Folder 336)
  - Friends and Relations - Barlow, Sir A. M., 1919-1953 (Box 45, Folder 337)
    British Member of Parliment (MP) interested in welfare work; friendship with John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    108B123
  - Friends and Relations - Benjamin, Florence and Wallace, 1902-1957 (Box 45, Folder 338)
    Florence with John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s niece; gifts; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to her children. Trusts established by John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Death of Lucy and Mrs. W. W. Benjamin.
    108B21
  - Friends and Relations - Benjamin, Mrs. F. A., 1934 (Box 45, Folder 339)
  - Friends and Relations - Benjamin, Mrs. W. W. - Gift of Standard Oil Stock, 1919-1920 (Box 45, Folder 340)
  - Friends and Relations - Benjamin, William D., 1920-1935; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 46, Folder 341)
    Crank, saw Laura Spelman Rockefeller in a vision; wanted a million dollars to build monastery in California.
    108B25
  - Friends and Relations - Benjamin, William D., 1935-1940; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 46, Folder 342)
  - Friends and Relations - Bennett, Dr. H. W. N., 1901-1959 (Box 46, Folder 343)
    Brown classmate of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; interested in providing pure milk for babies. Starr J. Murphy studied proposals; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. loan to buy farm. Later gifts.
    108B3
  - Friends and Relations - Bennett, John E., 1914-1916 (Box 46, Folder 344)
    Economist commented on Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I) representation plan.
    108B31
  - Friends and Relations - Biddle, A. J. D., 1921-1922 (Box 46, Folder 345)
    In Philadelphia Bible class; invitations to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined.
    108B5
  - Friends and Relations - Bird, Remson D., 1950-1957 (Box 47, Folder 346)
    California friend of Martha Baird Rockefeller; wrote John D. Rockefeller, Jr. regarding world peace and development.
    108B51
  - Friends and Relations - Biggar, Dr. H. F., 1904-1926 (Box 47, Folder 347)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s physician; visits, gifts.
  - Friends and Relations - Bishop, Dr. E. S., 1915-1935 (Box 47, Folder 348)
    Interested in drug addiction; aided by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    108B52
  - Friends and Relations - Bishop, J. M., 1905-1932 (Box 47, Folder 349)
    Retired customs official asked for aid; declined.
    108B532
  - Friends and Relations - Bixon, Mrs. F. B., 1929-1935 (Box 47, Folder 350)
    Aid to widow of Bible-Class man.
    108B53
  - Friends and Relations - Blair, Col. Henry T., 1941-1955 (Box 48, Folder 351)
    Social climber; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. finally asked him to stop writing and calling.
    108B54
  - Friends and Relations - Blakemore, Edward, 1903-1926 (Box 48, Folder 352)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. coachman; salary, gifts.
    108B6
  - Friends and Relations - Blessing, George F. and Mrs., 1917-1930 (Box 48, Folder 353)
    Industrial relations man, studied Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I) for John D. Rockefeller, Jr. His suggestions. Aid to his widow.
  - Friends and Relations - Bosworth, Welles, 1914-1919; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 48, Folder 354)
    Architect, helped with Pocantico Gardens, French restorations, importation of French Art. His life in France; gifts.
    108B71
  - Friends and Relations - Bosworth, Welles, 1940-1950; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 48, Folder 355)
  - Friends and Relations - Bosworth, Welles, 1939-1948; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 48, Folder 355A)
  - Friends and Relations - Bosworth, Welles, 1952-1962; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 49, Folder 356)
  - Friends and Relations - Bosworth, Welles, 1955-1960; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 49, Folder 0356A)
  - Friends and Relations - Boulware, A. L., 1921-1927 (Box 49, Folder 357)
    Tax man, 1921-1923; death; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid part of expenses.
    108B711
  - Friends and Relations - Bowers, L. M., 1902-1948 (Box 49, Folder 358)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. agent in Cleveland, was Frederick T. Gates' uncle; became Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I) director. Comments on Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I) strike, Bessemer Steamship Company, first job with Rockefeller.
    108B72
  - Friends and Relations - Bowers, L. M. (Box 49, Folder 359)
  - Friends and Relations - Bowers, L. M. - Salary, 1896-1920 (Box 49, Folder 360)
  - Friends and Relations - Bramen, Dwight, 1922-1927 (Box 49, Folder 361)
    Member of patriotic society; reaction to Red Scare; regarding immigrant education.
    108B74
  - Friends and Relations - Breasted, Dr. James, 1932-1959 (Box 49, Folder 362)
    Egyptologist associated with University of Chicago; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gifts; friendly correspondence.
    108B75
  - Friends and Relations - Breasted, Dr. James - Gift, 1929-1936 (Box 49, Folder 363)
  - Friends and Relations - Briggs, Mrs. Pierson, 1923-1940 (Box 50, Folder 364)
    Second wife of P. D. Briggs, who had been married to John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s sister Lucy Rockefeller formerly. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. visited Mrs. Briggs; friendly letters. Her death.
    108B76
  - Friends and Relations - Brookes, Reverand George S., 1917-1944 (Box 50, Folder 365)
    Seal Harbor minister, helped by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for college costs, medical care.
    108B78
  - Friends and Relations - Brooks, Reverand Arthur T., 1917-1939 (Box 50, Folder 366)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr. gifts to Baptist minister who worked at Tarrytown, Boston.
    108B79
  - Friends and Relations - Browning, John A., 1901-1930 (Box 50, Folder 367)
    Ran Browning School attended by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and John D. Rockefeller 3rd; tutored Nelson A. Rockefeller. Small gifts.
    108B82
  - Friends and Relations - Brush, M. C., 1907-1927 (Box 50, Folder 368)
    Worked in Boston Railrods, business friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. wanted to work in office.
    108B83
  - Friends and Relations - Buttrick Family, 1926-1961 (Box 50, Folder 369)
    Caroline B. was mentally unbalanced; sent crank letters. Ignored.
    108B84
  - Friends and Relations - Burton, Miss Margaret, 1954-1961 (Box 51, Folder 370)
    Friend of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, daughter of University of Chicago head and friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; helped Mary Ellen Chase write her Abby Aldrich Rockefeller biography; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts during illness totalled about $50,000.
    108B85
  - Friends and Relations - Bushnell, Ericson, 1907-1917 (Box 51, Folder 371)
    Grocer was golf friend of John D. Rockefeller, Sr.; requested loan; refused.
    108B9
  - Friends and Relations - Byrd, Richard E., 1936-1960 (Box 51, Folder 372)
    Friendship; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s personal gifts to him; annual gifts of apples from Byrd. Granite from Rockefeller Mountains in Antarctica.
  - Friends and Relations - Byrd, Richard E., 1949-1959 (Box 51, Folder 0372A)
  - Friends and Relations - Christ, Valentine, 1897-1925 (Box 51, Folder 373)
    Payment of $16,000 loan; mortgage on Christ's land.
    108C
  - Friends and Relations - Campbell, Percival, 1935-1959 (Box 51, Folder 374)
    Met John D. Rockefeller, Jr.. in Sicily; personal friendship.
  - Friends and Relations - Campbell, J. A., 1914-1921 (Box 51, Folder 375)
    City magistrate sought John D. Rockefeller, Jr. endorsements; didn't get them.
    108C1
  - Friends and Relations - Campbell, N. Stuart - Illness, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 376)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's sister Elsie; first husband, M. Edgell. Gifts to her, interest in her children; aid to her husband in final illness.
  - Friends and Relations - Campbell, Mrs. N. Stuart - Helena Edgell, 1945-1953 (Box 52, Folder 377)
  - Friends and Relations - Campbell, Mrs. N. Stuart - Stephen Edgell, 1927-1956 (Box 52, Folder 378)
  - Friends and Relations - Cain, Jo, 1932-1936 (Box 52, Folder 379)
    Mural painter; small support, some interest shown by Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    108C2
  - Friends and Relations - Cammerer, Arno B., 1924-1952 (Box 52, Folder 380)
    Personal friendship with National Park director; gifts during illness.
  - Friends and Relations - Cammerer, Arno B. - Illness Letters, 1926-1941 (Box 52, Folder 381)
  - Friends and Relations - Case, Helena, 1919-1920 (Box 52, Folder 382)
    Investment advice to Rhode Island friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    108C3
  - Friends and Relations - Calverley, Amice, 1936-1961 (Box 52, Folder 383)
    Egyptologist; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. assisted her work at Abydos; aid during illness.
  - Friends and Relations - Cannon, C. A., 1941-1953 (Box 52, Folder 384)
    News of colonial restoration activities in North Carolina.
    108C31
  - Friends and Relations - Chipman, Miner, 1915-1927 (Box 52, Folder 385)
    Efficiency engineer, commented on Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I) plan; W. L. M. King's comments.
    108C32
  - Friends and Relations - Chorley, Kenneth, 1939-1960 (Box 52, Folder 386)
    Personal friendship; gifts to him; his illnesses.
    108C41
  - Friends and Relations - Chorley, Kenneth - Personal Expenses, 1947-1956 (Box 52, Folder 387)
  - Friends and Relations - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1950-1951; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 53, Folder 388)
    Long, sparkling letters about Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's biography, school work, home in Maine; illness, retirement. Also correspondence with Dorothy Blaire regarding Miss Chase.
    108C42
  - Friends and Relations - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1950-1951; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 53, Folder 0388A)
  - Friends and Relations - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1951-1958; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 53, Folder 389)
  - Friends and Relations - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1952-1958; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 53, Folder 0389A)
  - Friends and Relations - Chase, Mary Ellen - Miss Dorothy Blair, 1950-1955 (Box 53, Folder 390)
  - Friends and Relations - Coakley, Dr. C. G., 1918-1935 (Box 53, Folder 391)
    Treated John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and some of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s friends.
    108C5
  - Friends and Relations - Clarke, Marshall, 1930-1943 (Box 53, Folder 392)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. aid to bankrupt florist.
  - Friends and Relations - Cogbill, William, 1926-1941 (Box 53, Folder 393)
    Office messenger; aid to children in getting jobs. Request for money after his death declined.
    108C6
  - Friends and Relations - Clapp, Frederick, 1934-1960 (Box 53, Folder 394)
    Aid in health matters; large gifts during his wife's illness.
  - Friends and Relations - Cohn, Harvey, 1935-1941 (Box 53, Folder 395)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller aid to Dartmouth track coach who lost job; job aid to his family.
    108C61
  - Friends and Relations - Colby, Everett, 1904-1922; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 54, Folder 396)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. college roommate, friend; comments on Ivy Lee, Colorado Fuel and Iron Company (CF&I), 18th amendment, family affairs. Description of visit to World War I battlefield. New Jersey law practice.
    108C7
  - Friends and Relations - Colby, Everett, 1923-1932; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 54, Folder 397)
  - Friends and Relations - Colby, Everett, 1933-1940; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 54, Folder 398)
  - Friends and Relations - Colby, Everett, 1940-1951; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 54, Folder 399)
  - Friends and Relations - Colby, Everett - Estate, 1943-1947; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 54, Folder 400)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. service as Executor; approval of trustees' actions.
    108C71
  - Friends and Relations - Colby, Everett - Estate, 1947-1951; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 54, Folder 401)
  - Friends and Relations - Colby, Everett, Jr., 1932-1950 (Box 54, Folder 402)
    Aid during mental illness; help getting a job.
    108C72
  - Friends and Relations - Cole, A. M., 1922-1937 (Box 55, Folder 403)
    Providence mailman carried Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's letters to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. while he was at Brown. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to him, 1923-1933.
    108C713
  - Friends and Relations - Conklin, W. R., 1928-1960 (Box 55, Folder 404)
    Attorney; legal fees; comments on decisions. Death.
    108C73
  - Friends and Relations - Cooper, Henry, 1907-1936 (Box 55, Folder 405)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s "older brother" in college; one time employee; joined Equitable Trust.
    108C75
  - Friends and Relations - Cox, John H., 1904-1931; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 55, Folder 406)
    Brown classmate, professor of English at West Virginia University. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. supplemented his salary, later paid him $100 per month.
    108C77
  - Friends and Relations - Cox, John H., 1931-1946; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 55, Folder 407)
  - Friends and Relations - Cuppy, H. A., 1905-1934 (Box 55, Folder 408)
    Small gifts to Bible class member; played golf with John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
    108C9
  - Friends and Relations - Dana, M. B., 1933-1935 (Box 55, Folder 409)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. aid for educational purposes to Seal Harbor part-time religious worker.
    108D1
  - Friends and Relations - Day, Frank L., 1912-1928 (Box 55, Folder 410)